let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "What does HTML stand for?",
    answer: "B. Hyper Text Markup Language",
    options: [
      "A. Hyper Text Preprocessor",
      "B. Hyper Text Markup Language",
      "C. Hyper Text Multiple Language",
      "D. Hyper Tool Multi Language"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "What does CSS stand for?",
    answer: "D. Cascading Style Sheet",
    options: [
      "A. Common Style Sheet",
      "B. Colorful Style Sheet",
      "C. Computer Style Sheet",
      "D. Cascading Style Sheet"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "What does PHP stand for?",
    answer: "A. Hypertext Preprocessor",
    options: [
      "A. Hypertext Preprocessor",
      "B. Hypertext Programming",
      "C. Hypertext Preprogramming",
      "D. Hometext Preprocessor"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "What does SQL stand for?",
    answer: "D. Structured Query Language",
    options: [
      "A. Stylish Question Language",
      "B. Stylesheet Query Language",
      "C. Statement Question Language",
      "D. Structured Query Language"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "What does XML stand for?",
    answer: "A. eXtensible Markup Language",
    options: [
      "A. eXtensible Markup Language",
      "B. eXecutable Multiple Language",
      "C. eXTra Multi-Program Language",
      "D. eXamine Multiple Language"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "What does TLS stand for?",
    answer: "B. Transport Layer Security",
    options: [
      "A. Transporting Layer Security",
      "B. Transport Layer Security",
      "C. Transportation Layer Security",
      "D. Transport Lower Security"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "What does FTP stand for?",
    answer: "C. File Transfer Protocol",
    options: [
      "A. File Transforming Protocol",
      "B. File Transfer Protection",
      "C. File Transfer Protocol",
      "D. File Transfering Protocol"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "What does URL stand for?",
    answer: "C. Uniform Resources Locator",
    options: [
      "A. Uniform Restoration Lacation",
      "B. Uniforming Resources Layer",
      "C. Uniform Resources Locator",
      "D. Uniform Resources Layout"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "In 1969 the precursor of internet is born:",
    answer: "B. ARPAnet",
    options: [
      "A. Google",
      "B. ARPAnet",
      "C. Internet",
      "D. Network"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "What does DNS stand  for?",
    answer: "D. Domain Name Saver",
    options:[
      "A. Domain Not Save",
      "B. Donating Nothing Saver",
      "C. Domain Name Save",
      "D. Domain Name Saver"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "What does ISP stand for?",
    answer: "C. Internet Service Provider",
    options: [
      "A. Internet Service Protocol",
      "B. Internal Service Provider",
      "C. Internet Service Provider",
      "D. Internet Service Protocol"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "The Web Technology is made up of?",
    answer: "C. HTML, CSS, Javascript",
    options:[
      "A. HTML, Python, React,",
      "B. Css, python, Javascript",
      "C. HTML, CSS, Javascript",
      "D. Database, Websaver, Domain"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "__ is the global system of interconnectioned computer networks.",
    answer: "D. Internet",
    options: [
      "A. Network",
      "B. Browser",
      "C. Website",
      "D. Internet"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question:" Which of the Hyperlink Uses a Word or Phrase?..",
    answer: "A. Text Hyperlink",
    options:[
      "A. Text Hyperlink",
      "B. Bookmark Hyperlink",
      "B. E-mial Hyperlink",
      "D. Image Hyperlink"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "An electronic tool that allows information to be input, processed, and output is called _______________",
    answer: "D. Computer",
    options:[
      "A. Operating System",
      "B. CPU",
      "C. Motherboard",
      "D. Computer"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "_____________ is a worldwide network of computers.",
    answer: "C. Internet",
    options:[
      "A. Server",
      "B. Router",
      "C. Internet",
      "D. RAM"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "Name the brain of the computer that does the calculation, moving, and processing of information.",
    answer: "D. CPU",
    options:[
      "A. Motherboard",
      "B. RAM",
      "C. Hard Disk",
      "D. CPU"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "What is the main component of a computer?",
    answer: "D. Processor",
    options:[
      "A. Battery",
      "B. Screen",
      "C. Keyboard",
      "D. Processor"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "How many bits does a byte have?",
    answer: "C. 8",
    options:[
      "A. 4",
      "B. 5",
      "C. 8",
      "D. 10"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Which type of memory has the fastest access time?",
    answer: "C. Cache Memory",
    options:[
      "A. Random Access Memory (RAM)",
      "B. Read-Only Memory (ROM)",
      "C. Cache Memory",
      "D. External Memory"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 21,
    question: "What is the purpose of BIOS in a computer?",
    answer: "B. Booting and Initializing the System",
    options:[
      "A. Protecting the Computer from Viruses",
      "B. Booting and Initializing the System",
      "C. Managing Disk Drives",
      "D. Providing User Access to the System"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 22,
    question: "What is the maximum number of disks that can be connected to a single motherboard?",
    answer: "B. Two",
    options:[
      "A. One",
      "B. Two",
      "C. Four",
      "D. Six"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 23,
    question: "What is the name of the software that is responsible for managing the computer?",
    answer: "D. Operating System (OS)",
    options:[
      "A. User Application Software",
      "B. Kernel",
      "C. Device Driver",
      "D. Operating System (OS)"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 24,
    question: "Which type of memory has a data retention rate of up to one year?",
    answer: "D. RAM (Random Access Memory)",
    options:[
      "A. ROM (Read-Only Memory)",
      "B. EPROM (Erasable Programmable Read-Only Memory)",
      "C. EEPROM (Electrically Erasable Programmable Read-Only",
      "D. RAM (Random Access Memory)"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 25,
    question: "How many bits are used in the address bus of a typical computer system?",
    answer: "B. 16 Bits",
    options:[
      "A. 8 Bits",
      "B. 16 Bits",
      "C. 24 Bits",
      "D. 32 Bits"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 26,
    question: "What is the term for the process by which a user can add new features or capabilities to an existing program?",
    answer: "D. Maintenance",
    options: [
      "A. Development",
      "B. Testing",
      "C. Deployment",
      "D. Maintenance"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 27,
    question: "What is the purpose of the Interrupt Request (IRQ) line in a microprocessor?",
    answer: "C. To signal an interrupt request from peripheral devices to the CPU.",
    options:[
      "A. To signal an interrupt request from the keyboard or other input/output devices to the CPU.",
      "B. To signal an interrupt request from the CPU to the keyboard or other input/output devices",
      "C. To signal an interrupt request from peripheral devices to the CPU.",
      "D. To signal an interrupt request from the timer device to the CPU."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 28,
    question: "Which type of memory has a write cycle time that is faster than read cycle time?",
    answer: "D. DRAM (Dynamic Random Access Memory)",
    options:[
      "A .SRAM (Static Random Access Memory)",
      "B. SDRAM (Single-Inferred DRAM)",
      "C. DDR RAM (Double Data Rate RAM)",
      "D. DRAM (Dynamic Random Access Memory)"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 29,
    question: "The most Common Operating Sysytem for work station are......",
    answer: "D. Unix and Windows NT",
    options:[
      "A. Dos and unix",
      "B. Unix and Linux",
      "C. Windows and Dos",
      "D. Unix and Windows NT"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 30,
    question: "Special purpose computer programs are sometimes called?...",
    answer: "A. Firm Ware",
    options:[
      "A. Firm Ware",
      "B. Mall Ware",
      "C. Soft Ware",
      "D. Hard Ware"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 31,
    question: ".... Is a computer design to fit comfortably on top of a desk, typically with the monitor sitting on top of the computer",
    answer: "C. Desktop Model",
    options:[
      "A. Tower Model",
      "B. Top Computer",
      "C. Desktop Model",
      "D. Top Model"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:32,
    question: "......... Is a handheld device that combines computing, telephone/fax and networking features.",
    answer: "A. Personal digital assistant (PDA)",
    options:[
      "A. Personal digital assistant (PDA)",
      "B. Personal computer",
      "C. Personal Information Computer",
      "D. Personal assistant"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:33,
    question: "Information is intrinsically meaningless on its own and remains so unless interpreted by..",
    answer: "C. Human beings",
    options:[
      "A. Computer",
      "B. Softwares",
      "C. Human beings",
      "D. Technology"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 34,
    question: "Mainframe computers are usually used in ......................... and as ................. in wide area networks",
    answer: "B. Centralized database and as control nodes",
    options:[
      "A. Internet and Network",
      "B. Centralized database and as control nodes",
      "C. Programming and Coding",
      "D. Database and Networking"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 35,
    question: "............. is the electronic centerpiece of the computer",
    answer:"A. Motherboard or Main board",
    options:[
      "A. Motherboard or Main board",
      "B. Processor",
      "C. Central Processing Unit (CPU)",
      "D. Board"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 36,
    question: ".......... Is any Process that a computer program does to enter data and summarize information",
    answer: "B. Computer data processing",
    options:[
      "A. Data processing",
      "B. Computer data processing",
      "C. Processing data",
      "D. Processing information"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 37,
    question: "The programs that special purpose computers run are installed permanently into .............. so that they cannot be deleted, edited or updated.",
    answer: "D. Read only memory",
    options: [
      "A. Read from computer",
      "B. Random Access Memory",
      "C. Hard Disk",
      "D. Read only memory"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 38,
    question: ".............. is a device that converts digital signals into analog.",
    answer: "A. Moderm",
    options:[
      "A. Moderm",
      "B. ROM",
      "C. RAM",
      "D. Data"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 39,
    question: "The processing of data using manual method is likely to be influenced by............... which will in turn, distort the integrity or value of information.",
    answer: "D. Human Error",
    options: [
      "A. Computer Error",
      "B. Precessing Error",
      "C. Data Error",
      "D. Human Error"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 40,
    question: "Depending on their flexibility in operation, computers are clasified as either ............. or .............",
    answer: "A. Special purpose computers or general purpose computers",
    options:[
      "A. Special purpose computers or general purpose computers",
      "B. Read only computers or Random Access Computers",
      "C. Digital computers or Analog Computers",
      "D. Portable computers or Personnal computers"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 41,
    question: "At the time of plato..........were two erroneous applications of justice which were against the ethical value of Greek",
    answer:"C. Thyrasymachus (means mighty or right)/ reciprocation of either good or evil to one's friend or foe respectively.",
    options:[
      "A. Thyrasyma (means mighty or right)/ reciprocation of either good or evil to one's friend or  friend of foe respectively.",
      "B. Tyrasymachus (means mighty or right)/ reciprocation of either good or evil to one's friend",
      "C. Thyrasymachus (means mighty or right)/ reciprocation of either good or evil to one's friend or foe respectively.",
      "D. Thyrasymachus (means mighty or right)/ reciprocation of either evil or evil to one's friend or foe respectively."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 42,
    question: "The soul has three parts which are ..........., ............. and ...............",
    answer: "A. Rational, Spirited and appetitive parts",
    options:[
      "A. Rational, Spirited and appetitive parts",
      "B. Rational, Demon and appetitive parts",
      "C. Rattional, Spirited and appetitive parts",
      "D. Rational, Spirited and approaching parts"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 43,
    question: "For Aristotle, the state owes every citizen the common good which is .........................",
    answer: "D. Happiness",
    options:[
      "A. Hope",
      "B. Love",
      "C. Joy",
      "D. Happiness"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 44,
    question: "The system of lawas a whole in the legal parlance is called............",
    answer: "B. The system of justice",
    options: [
      "A. The system of Peace",
      "B. The system of justice",
      "C. system or justice",
      "D. The system of wickedness"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 45,
    question: "What a man is entitled to as a matter of justice is called ............",
    answer: "A. Right",
    options: [
      "A. Right",
      "B. Righthood",
      "C. Wrong",
      "D. Right law"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 46,
    question: "............is the most universal and powerfull of all social institution.",
    answer: "A. The state",
    options: [
      "A. The state",
      "B. The Government",
      "C. The president",
      "D. The Governor"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 47,
    question: "The four constituent of the modern state are ...............",
    answer: "A. Population, territory, governmenty and sovereignt",
    options:[
      "A. Population, territory, governmenty and sovereignt",
      "B. power, territory, governmenty and sovereignt",
      "C. Population, territory, governmenty and School",
      "D. Population, political, governmenty and sovereignt"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 48,
    question: "Sovereignty is derived from the latin word.................... meaning supreme",
    answer: "B. Superanus",
    options: [
      "A. Superman",
      "B. Superanus",
      "C. Supreme",
      "D. Super"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 49,
    question: "Assembly line, robots, rocket telemetry processing, flight system, industrial automation and control system are eaxamples of  ............ precessing.",
    answer: "D. Real time Processing",
    options: [
      "A. Precessing",
      "B. Information Processing",
      "C. Automatic Processing",
      "D. Real time Processing"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 50,
    question: "Data in RAM is lost when the computer is .............",
    answer: "C. Powered down",
    options: [
      "A. Powered on",
      "B. switched off",
      "C. Powered down",
      "D. Switched on"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 51,
    question: "The processing of data using manual method is likely to be influenced by............... which will in turn, distort the integrity or value of information.",
    answer: "A. Human Error",
    options: [
      "A. Human Error",
      "B. Precessing Error",
      "C. Data Error",
      "D. Computer Error"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 52,
    question: ".......... Is any Process that a computer program does to enter data and summarize information",
    answer: "A. Data processing",
    options:[
      "A. Data processing",
      "B. Data progressing",
      "C. Processing data",
      "D. Processing information"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 53,
    question: "......... is the term for the process by which a Programmer or a Developer can add new features or capabilities to an existing program?",
    answer: "B. Maintenance",
    options: [
      "A. Assembly",
      "B. Maintenance",
      "C. Compiling",
      "D. Editing"
    ]
  }
];
